Finding Aid for Malcolm Keith Hatfield Papers, 1930-1961
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Malcolm Keith Hatfield papers 1930-1961
Hatfield, Malcolm Keith, 1900-1961.
851449 Aa 2
Berrien County judge; correspondence and other papers largely relating to topic of juvenile delinquency.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
3 linear feet
The collection was the gift of Mrs. Cordelia Hatfield (donor no. 5246 ) and came to the library in 1972.
The collection is open to research.
Malcolm Hatfield served as a probate judge of Berrien County, Michigan,1933-1954. He also lectured and wrote on the subject of juvenile delinquency.
The collection includes correspondence, an autobiographical sketch in fictional form, manuscripts of articles and short stories, speeches, and scrapbooks. The collection has been arranged into the following series: Correspondence; Juvenile Delinquency; Miscellaneous; Short Stories; and Photographs.
Subjects:
Berrien County (Mich.); Elections--Michigan--1948.; Hatfield, Malcolm Keith, 1900-1961.; Judges--Michigan--Berrien County.; Juvenile delinquency--Michigan.; Law.; Saint Joseph (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
African Americans--Michigan.; Erosion.; Hatfield, Malcolm Keith, 1900-1961.; Hatfield family.; Judges--Michigan--Berrien County.; Michigan, Lake.; Military uniforms.; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People--Michigan.; Offices--1931-1940.; World War, 1914-1918.
Contributors:
Dickinson, Luren Dudley, 1859-1943.; Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976.; Green, William, 1870-1952.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Sloan, Alfred P. (Alfred Pritchard), 1875-1966.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Correspondence 1930-1960
  - Undated 1930-1960, 33 folders (Box 1)
- Juvenile Delinquency
  - Manuscripts of newspaper columns on juvenile delinquency, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Papers concerning juvenile delinquency in Berrien County (Box 2)
  - Report of a survey entitled, "The Juvenile Court, Detention Home and Related Agencies, Berrien County (St. Joseph), Michigan" 1948 (Box 2)
  - Auditor Reports on Berrien County Probate Court 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Printed material on juvenile delinquency (Box 2)
  - Materials concerning judicial system and mental illness (Box 2)
  - Materials concerning emotional problems and juvenile delinquency (Box 2)
  - Commentary on the relationship between modernization and juvenile delinquency (Box 2)
  - Materials on the Service Guild and its publication Self-Analysis (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Campaign materials
    - Materials related to judicial elections 1944-1956 (Box 2)
    - Clippings on judicial elections, particularly the election of 1948, 1944-1956 (Box 2)
    - Nomination petitions for the Second Circuit Court election 1954 (Box 2)
  - Speeches (Box 2)
  - Assorted materials, including notebooks and manual concerning First Service Command Tactical School 1942 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - General (Box 2)
    - Newspaper clippings of reviews of book Children in Court (Box 2)
  - Scrapbooks, 2 volumes (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook concerning Judicial election, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Manuscript of Parents on Probation (Box 3)
- Short Stores:
  - Playing God (Box 3)
  - The Angels Fly Low (Box 3)
    (autobiographical sketch)
  - The Barbarians (Box 3)
  - Remember Your Temper (Box 3)
  - Shorn Lamb (Box 3)
  - Guerrilla Warfare (Box 3)
  - Green Grapes (Box 3)
  - The Lamps Went Out (Box 3)
  - Susan Was Wed in Korea (Box 3)
  - Susan Was Wed on Saturday (Box 3)
  - The Stone That Was Rejected (Box 3)
- Photographs
  - Family and individual portraits; photos of NAACP meeting; photos of damage in Benton Harbor because of soil erosion (Box 3)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Dickinson, Luren Dudley, 1859-1943.
March 30, 1939
Farley, James Aloysius, 1888-
June 27, 1940, March 27, 1952, April 21, 1952
Green, William, 1870-1952.
May 23, 1938, June 2, 1938, March 18, 1940
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
April 21, 1938
Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.
May 24, 1938, January 23, 1940
Sloan, Alfred P. (Alfred Pritchard), 1875-1966.
May 25, 1938
Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.
August 4, 1951